You now have a basic understanding of probability. Great job!
لديك الآن فهم أساسي لمدى الاحتمالية.
Let's quickly summarize what was covered in this lesson.
دعونا نلخص بسرعة ما تم تضمينه في هذا الدرس.
You learned about the probability of an event.
تعلمت عن احتمال وقوع حدث ما.
Such as the outcome of a coin flip.
مثل نتيجة الاقتراع بالعلمة المعدنية.
You learned that the probability of
لقد تعلمت أن احتمال حدوث
the opposite event is one minus the probability of this event.
حدث معاكس هو احتمال واحد من احتمالات هذا الحدث.
And you learned about the probability of a composite event,
كما تعلمت عن احتمال وجود حدث مركب،
which was in the form of P times P times P and so on.
والذي كان في شكل P في بعض الأحيان وفي أشكال أخرى أحيانًا.
This rule is true because the events we've
هذه القاعدة صحيحة لأن الأحداث التي
observed so far are independent of one another,
لاحظناها حتى الآن هي أحداث مستقلة عن بعضها البعض،
which means the outcome of one event doesn't affect the outcome of another,
مما يعني أن نتيجة حدث ما لا تؤثر على نتيجة حدث آخر،
which is also the case in the next lesson on binomial distributions.
وهو ما يحدث أيضًا في الدرس التالي الذي يتناول عمليات التوزيع ثنائية الحد.
However, if we're looking at the probability of dependent events,
ومع ذلك، إذا نظرنا إلى احتمالية حدوث أحداث غير مستقلة،
say the probability of rain tomorrow given that it rained today, this rule doesn't hold.
يمكننا القول باحتمال هطول الأمطار غدًا نظرًا لهطول الأمطار اليوم، وهذه القاعدة ليست ثابتة.
Dependent events where the outcomes of later events depend
كانت الأحداث غير المستقلة تمثل نتائج الأحداث اللاحقة التي تعتمد
on what has already happened are at the heart of the following topics,
على ما حدث بالفعل أو ما هو في صميم المواضيع التالية،
unconditional probability and Bayes Rule.
والاحتمال غير المشروط وقاعدة Bayes.